<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Felicity McEnnulty and Anthony J. Richardson on Dr Jason Everett</title>
    <link>/authors/felicity-mcennulty-and-anthony-j.-richardson/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Felicity McEnnulty and Anthony J. Richardson on Dr Jason Everett</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019 Jason D. Everett; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 17:10:44 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="/authors/felicity-mcennulty-and-anthony-j.-richardson/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Australian Zooplankton Biomass</title>
      <link>/project/mapping_zooplankton_biomass/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 17:10:44 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/mapping_zooplankton_biomass/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Zooplankton biomass data have been collected in Australian waters since the 1930s, yet most datasets have been unavailable to the research community. We have collated &amp;gt;15,000 records of marine zooplankton biomass from Australian waters. Many of these are small-scale datasets, but when combined, they provide over 85 years of large-scale zooplankton community biomass data for Australian waters from 1932 to the present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using generalised additive models (GAMs) based on a suite of environmental variables including sea surface temperature, chlorophyll-a and depth, we are producing spatial maps of zooplankton biomass in Australian waters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The end goal is for these maps to be provided to the community as model-ready data products. The Australian Zooplankton Biomass Database and associated modelled-products will be invaluable for global change studies, research assessing trophic level linkages, and for initialising and assessing biogeochemical and ecosystem models of lower trophic levels.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
